Richard Wormser Papers 1932-1977 (bulk 1934-1973)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Richard Wormser Papers 1932-1977 (bulk 1934-1973)
MS 579
Richard Wormser
This collection contains manuscripts and published editions of short stories, novels, film and television screenplays and relevant correspondence covering the writing career of Richard Wormser who began his career as a pulp magazine story writer and ended up a novelist who wrote screenplays for Hollywood. The genres he mostly worked in were Westerns and Mysteries.
11.3 Linear Feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
This collection contains manuscripts of short stories, novels, film and television screenplays and relevant correspondence covering the writing career of Richard Wormser, who began his career as a pulp magazine story writer and ended up a novelist who wrote screenplays for Hollywood. The genres he mostly worked in were Westerns and Mysteries.
Wormser became a writer of short stories and serialized novels for a number of the better known pulp magazines of the day including Argosy, Blue Book and Detective Fiction Weekly. As Wormser became more successful, his stories were adapted as scripts for movies and television. Wormser colorfully describes his time with the pulp magazines in his autobiography, How to Become a Complete Nonentity.
As the US entered the Second World War, Wormser moved out west where he worked as a horseback patrolman for the Forest Service in southern California while continuing to write for magazines and Hollywood during his evenings. After the war he moved in Santa Fe before finally settling in Tubac, Arizona.
Wormser was also asked by editors to produce informative text for encyclopedias and he had an interest in writing about culinary topics as well as the history, culture and topography of the American Southwest. Richard Wormser died in Tubac, Arizona in 1977.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series
Series I: Manuscripts, 1934-1975
Subseries 1: Titled manuscripts of fictional works, 1934-1973
Subseries 2: Untitled manuscripts, Undated
Subseries 3: Nonfiction Manuscripts, 1955-1975
Subseries 4: Manuscripts related to cooking, 1955-1969
Series II: Personal and business materials, 1951-1977
Subseries 1: Autobigraphical material, 1957-1977
Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1951-1977
Series III: Oversized materials, 1936-1955
Scope and Content Note
This collection was donated by Wormser’s widow and covers most of his career (1934-1976).
Series One consists of his manuscripts. The first subseries, the bulk of the collection, is composed of titled fictional stories of various length ranging from short stories to novelettes to novels as well as screenplays for film and television. Many of the manuscripts are organized with published editions of the stories in pulp magazines, complete with characteristicly lurid covers and illustrations. Titles where Wormser contributed frequently include Argosy, Bluebook, Detective Fiction Weekly, and Saturday Evening Post. Many of these manuscripts are grouped with relevant correspondence between Wormser and his literary agents detailing the ins and outs of the publishing trade.
The second subseries consists of Wormser’s untitled manuscripts.
Series Two consists of Wormser’s personal and business materials. Subseries one is made up of several autobiographies written at different points in his career. Subseries two is his correspondence, mostly professional with fan letters, it is preserved in his original order.
Series Three consists of Wormser’s published stories in large format magazines.
Access Terms
Richard Wormser.
Authors, American – 20th Century -- Sources.
Short stories
Novels
Screenplays
Correspondence
Writer
Container List
- Manuscripts, 1934-1975; Series 1
  Folders are described by title where available, genre, format, notes (if any) and date.
  - Titled manuscripts of fictional works, 1934-1975; Subseries 1
    - All Cooks are Crazy, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amber, Treatment, Typewritten MS, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Babbling Voice, Short story, Detective Ficton Weekly, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Back to Paris, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Banker, TV treatment, Typewritten MS, Treatment for "Lawman" TV series, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Beals Mountain, Short story, Argosy Magazine, correspondence in folder, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Beat the Drums Slowly, Novel, Typewritten MS, Damaged MS, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Big County, Short Story, Typewritten MS, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bigshot From Alcatraz (1 of 2), Short story, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bigshot From Alcatraz (2 of 2), Short story, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Birthday of a Stooge, Short story, Typewritten MS, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - The Blanket Indian, Short story, Typewritten MS, Folder also contains incomplete MS called "Politico", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Blood Brother, Novel, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Blues for a Lonely Egghead (1 of 2), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Blues for a Lonely Egghead (2 of 2), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Body in the Rain, Short story, Star Detective Magazine, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Body Looks Familiar, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Body Looks Familiar (Org. The Golden Frame), Drafts, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - The Bouncing Chip, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, "77 Sunset Strip", 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Brasada Story, Treatment, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Brass Legend, Screenplay, Shooting script, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Break in the Journey, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Breaks of the Humboldt (1 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, book-length MS with summary of uncompleted ending, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Breaks of the Humboldt (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, Later published as "Slattery's Range", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bring'em Back Dead, Short story, Argosy Magazine, Several drafts in folder, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bringing in the Bandit, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Brink of Fear, TV script, Shooting script, "Sugarfoot" TV series, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Burning Herd, Short story, Typewritten MS, Written during his NYC years, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Busy Day, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Buzz Saw (1 of 2), Short story, Bluebook Magazine, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Buzz Saw (2 of 2), Correspondence and Story, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - By Any Other Name, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Camels on the Sage, Novelette, Argosy Magazine, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Captain Boss-buster, Short story, Detective Action Stories, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Captain Retires, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Carnival Queen (1 of 2), Short story, Typewritten MS, SSs: Merry Go-Round Broke Down; McNally & the Executive Lion; Manhattan Quail; Gorilla Cargo, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Carnival Queen (2 of 2), Serialized Story, Argosy Magazine, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Change of Address, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Clew on the Cane, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Cold Tropic Hell, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Company Money, Short story, Saturday Evening Post, Contains several drafts as "Trouble Shooter", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Copper the Bet, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Count the Dead, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Counterpoint, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Country Store, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Courtship of Baptiste Brown, The, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Crime's Tax, Short story, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dark Canyon, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Dark Mustanger, Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Dead Tycoon, Novel length work published in magazine, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Death Over the Riviera, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Deceptive Wife, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Dinner Date, Short story, Typewritten MS, Several drafts in folder, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Double Justice, TV script, Typewritten MS, Screenplay. Treatments and multiple drafts, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Drought, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Drums of Doom, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Dumb Cowpoke (1 of 2), (TV), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The Dumb Cowpoke (2 of 2), Novelette, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The Election at Nopal, TV script, Typewritten MS, "Cheyenne" TV show, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Drums of Doom, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Elephants to Ride Upon, Short story, Typewritten MS, Multiple drafts in folder, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - The Fearful Heart, Novellette, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Featherfingers Takes a Drink, Film Script, Typewritten MS, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Fight City Hall, Story basis for TV movie, Typewritten MS, "Two-hour TV movie, possibly a series", undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - The Finger of the Law, Short story, Black Book Detective, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Fire Extinguisher, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - First Crush, Short story, Liberty Magazine, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - First Gun at the Wedding, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - First Lesson, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - The First Rung, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Flash Flood, Short story, Cosmopolitan, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Flowering Apricot, Short story, Typewritten MS, another untitled MS in folder, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Follow Your Heart, TV script, Shooting script, "The High Chaparral" TV show, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Fool in the Rendez-Vous, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Fort Dodge Stampede, Screenplay, Shooting script, Folder contains screenplay plus correspondence re: The "Half-Breed", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Four O'Clock, Short Story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Framed Fish, Unfinished Novel, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Friend, TV script, Shooting script, "The Lawman" TV series, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Frontier Fury, treatment, Typewritten MS, Bound in Universal Pictures folder, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The Gang, TV script, Shooting script, "The Lawman" TV series, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Gentlemen's Business (Unpublished), Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Ghost Town, TV script, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - The Girl Was Bored, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Goats, TV Script, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, "Lassie" TV show, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The Gold Plated Years, TV show treatment, Typewritten MS, "A tale of restless retirees", undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Gone to Texas, Novel, Typewritten MS, Draft of a Novel, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Graves at Brian's Bench, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Gunslick, Short story, Typewritten MS, Originally titled "Johnny Ride the Prairie", Correspondence in folder, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Hair of Brother, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Havoc on the Hudson, Short story, Liberty Magazine, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Home from the Hills, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - The Honeypot, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - The Honeypot (1 of 2) Novel, Typewritten MS, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Honeypot (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Hong Kong Caper, TV script, Shooting script, "77 Sunset Strip" TV show, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Honky-Tonk Street, Novelette, Typewritten MS, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Honour, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - A Horse at Heart, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Horse Money, Novelette, Bluebook Magazine, MS also in folder, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Hosteen Yazzie, Synopsis for juvenile story, Typewritten MS, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hot Enough, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - House of Clay, Outline, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - How Good a Detective are You?, Prose puzzles, Detective Fiction Weekly, Puzzle of the Cornered Bandits & Puzzle of the Dead Sheriff, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Hunch Player, Short story, Detective Story Magazine, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Hunter, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - I Sell Strikes, Short Novel, Detective Fiction Weekly, Correspondence in folder, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - I'll Show You the Town, Short story, Typewritten MS, Two drafts in folder, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - I'm No Sucker, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Isle of Yellow Girls, Short story, Argosy Magazine, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - It Takes an Artist, Short story, Typewritten MS, circa 1945-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Jack O' Diamonds, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Jeff Duane & The Lady, TV script, Typewritten MS, Script for "Zane Grey Theater" TV show, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Joe Cafferty, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - John Gay Makes a Killing, Short story, Cavalcade, Three MSs for John Gay Stories in folder also includes: John Gay Dons the Hood and John Gay Sells a Frame, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Johnny Ride the Prairie, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Junk's Worth Money, Short Story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - The Killer's Pawn, Short story, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - King of the Mountain, Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Kingdom by the Sea, Novel, Bluebook Magazine, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - The Lady from Hooliganville, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Last Stage West, Film treatment, Typewritten MS, circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Let the Young Men Smoke, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Life Follows Art, Short story, Typewritten MS, circa 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Life of Vernon Hathaway, Short story, Typewritten MS, circa 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Live Cargo, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Locker 911, Novelette, Manhunt Magazine, Org. Title: Fresh Start, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Loco Killer, The, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Lonely Lady, Pity Me, TV script, Shooting script, "77 Sunset Strip" TV show, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Long Ago and Far Away, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - The Long Twilight, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Low Pockets, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Lucky McNally, Short story, Argosy Magazine, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - The Mabra Pinch, Short story, Black Book Detective, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Macbeth, Screenplay, Shooting script, Screenplay for Orson Welles' film production, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - The Madrona Tree, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Magoffin, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Make Your Bet, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Man Power, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Man With a Shiv, Novelette, Manhunt Magazine, Correspondence in folder, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - The Manbuster, Short story, This Week, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Man-Eater, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - McGlusky's Lucky Day, Novelette, Argosy Magazine, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - McNally, I'm Afraid, Novelette, Argosy Magazine, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - McSmith Was Right, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - The Meanest Racket, Short story, Typewritten MS, "for Detective Fiction magazine", undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Medals for McNally, Short story, Argosy Magazine, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Medicine Man, TV script, Shooting script, "Steve Donovan- Western Marshal" TV series, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Melody Morgan, Short story, Typewritten MS, three drafts in folder, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Microphone Masquerade, Serialized Story, Radio Mirror, Novel serialized over four issues, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Mister Murder Goes to Town, Novel, Detective Tales, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Money into Thin Air, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mountain Doctor, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Mountains, the Plains and the Time (1 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Mountains, the Plains and the Time (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - My Friend Flicka, TV script treatment, Typewritten MS, Writer's Brief included in folder, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Navajo Country, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Needle Nose Mac, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Neurotic, The, Novel, Typewritten MS, a.k.a. The Expanse of Fear, Novel by Mrs. Wormser/Judith Gordon, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - The New Spurs, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, Correspondence in folder, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Nick Carter Magazine (1 of 2), Pulp Magazine edited by Wormser, circa 1934 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Nick Carter Magazine (2 of 2), Pulp Magazine edited by Wormser, circa 1934 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The Night Beals Mountain Burned, Short story, Argosy Magazine, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Night Call, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, Correspondence in folder, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - No Dogs Allowed, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Old Country, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Old Pumprop (1 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Old Pumprop (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Once and Again, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Outlandish Mountain, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Outside the Law, Short story, Argosy Magazine, Correspondence in folder, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - The Paper World, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - The Paper World, (Copy- Fragile), Novel, Typewritten MS, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Paradise for a Dime, TV script, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Paradise for a Dime (teleplay), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Parson From Boot Hill, Short story, Adventure Magazine, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Pass Through Manhattan (1 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Pass Through Manhattan (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Patrol (a.k.a. Man Hunt), Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - The Peace in Anderson, Screenplay, Shooting Script, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - The Peaceful Countryside, Mystery Novelette, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - The Pillroller, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - A Pinch From the Grave, Short story, Black Book Detective, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Procession, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Programmed for Death, TV script, Shooting script, Green Hornet TV show, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - The Proud Sheriff, TV script, Typewritten MS, Episode from "Cheyenne" TV show, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Push Your Luck, Short story, Typewritten MS, Formerly titled "Pigeon Money", undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - The Quest of Willie Hunter, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - The Quiet Guys, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - The Racket Smashers, (Parts 1, 2, and 4), Serialized Story, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - The Racket Smashers, (Parts 5, 6, 7 and 8), Serialized Story, Detective Fiction Weekly, correspodence in folder, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - The Racket Smashers, (Parts 5, 6, 7 and 8), Serialized Story, Detective Fiction Weekly, correspodence in folder, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - The Ranch by the Sea, (short story), Short story, Typewritten MS, Includes published version as "Kingdom by the Sea", 1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - The Ranch by the Sea (1 of 2), Short story, Typewritten MS, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Ranch by the Sea (2 of 2), Galley draft, Typewritten MS, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - The Rare Wines of Manhattan, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - The Red Pony, Screenplay, Shooting script, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Red Skies of Montana, Screenplay, Shooting script, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Reporter at Large, Short Novel, Bluebook Magazine, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - The Riddle of the Redhead, Novelette, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Ride a Northbound Horse, Novel, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Riot at Arroyo Seco, TV script, Typewritten MS, "Cheyenne" TV show, aired Feb. 1, 1960, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - The Road to Carmichael's, treatment, Typewritten MS, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - The Road to Riches, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - The Rough Hand, Novelette, Argosy Magazine, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - The Royal Bodyguard, Novelette, All Star Adventure Fiction, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Rustlers on Horseback, Film treatment, Typewritten MS, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - The Sagebrush Quarter, Novel, Typewritten MS, Published as "The Lonesome Quarter", 1951 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - The Scalphunters, Novel, Typewritten MS, MS is severely damaged, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Second Wind, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Sewed Up, Short Novel, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Shadow in Blood, Short story, Star Detective Magazine, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Shadow of a Man (Screenplay), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 5)